Inventory of the Herard von Santos M. interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
Herard von Santos M. interviews
undated
2009C49
Hoover Institution Archives
1 computer disc (1 manuscript box) (0.4 linear feet)
Digital sound recordings and transcripts of interviews of former Salvadoran military officers and guerrillas, relating to guerrilla warfare and counterinsurgency operations in El Salvador in the 1970s and 1980s.
Santos M., Herard von (Santos Méndez), 1966-, interviewer.
Access
The collection is open for research. Use copies of all sound recordings available.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Digital sound recordings and transcripts of interviews of former Salvadoran military officers and guerrillas, relating to guerrilla warfare and counterinsurgency operations in El Salvador in the 1970s and 1980s.
Frente Farabundo Martí para la Liberación Nacional.; El Salvador--History--1979-1992.; Guerrillas--El Salvador.
Collection Contents
- Sound Recordings, 2000-2009 (Other Reading room workstation)
  - Interview with Cap. José Raúl Álvarez Tavora on 10 Feb 2009, 10 February 2009
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002501
    Scope and Contents note
    Cap. José Raúl Álvarez Tavora
    Fecha de la entrevista: 10 de febrero de 2009
    Lugar: San Salvador, El Salvador
    Veterano del Batallón de Infantería de Reacción Inmediata Atonal.
  - Interview with Cap. Jurgûen Hesse Hoya in Jun 2003, 31 May 2003
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002502
    Cap. Jurgûen Hesse Hoya
    Fecha de la entrevista: junio de 2003
    Lugar: Tegucigalpa, Honduras
    Veterano de la Fuerza Aérea Hondureña, piloto de helicóptero UH-1H.
  - Interview with Cnel. Carlos Duarte Orozco on 6 Sep 2005, 06 September 2005
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002504
    Cnel. Carlos Duarte Orozco
    Fecha de la entrevista: 6 de septiembre de 2005
    Managua, Nicaragua
    Jefe del Estado Mayor de la Brigada de Infantería Mecanizada del Ejército de Nicaragua
  - Interview with Cnel. Carlos Reynaldo López Nuila in Jul 2006, 30 June 2006
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002509
    Cnel. Carlos Reynaldo López Nuila
    Fecha de la entrevista: julio de 2006
    Ex-Director de la Policía Nacional de El Salvador
  - Interview with Cnel. Francisco Elena Fuentes on 20 Jun 2006, 20 June 2006
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002505
    Cnel. Francisco Elena Fuentes
    Fecha de la entrevista: 20 de junio de 2006
    San Salvador, El Salvador
    Ex-Comandante de la 1ra. Brigada de Infantería (Cuartel San Carlos) del Ejército de El Salvador.
  - Interview with Cnel. Jorge Hugo Flores Arana on 6 Dec 2002, 06 December 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002506
    Cnel. Jorge Hugo Flores Arana
    Fecha de la entrevista: 6 de diciembre 2002
    Lugar: Puerto de San José, Guatemala
    Comandante de la Brigada de Paracaidistas del Ejército de Guatemala
  - Interview with Cnel. Jorge Ramón Arnesto Souza in Aug 2000, 31 July 2000
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002503
    Cnel. Jorge Ramón Arnesto Souza
    Fecha de la entrevista: agosto 2000
    Lugar: Managua, Nicaragua
    Jefe del Departamento de Relaciones Públicas y Exteriores del Ejército de Nicaragua
  - Interview with Cnel. José Humberto Guzmán Cáceres on 27 Jun 2007, 27 June 2007
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002507
    Cnel. José Humberto Guzmán Cáceres
    Fecha de la entrevista: 27 de junio de 2007
    Ex-Comandante del Regimiento de Caballería del Ejército salvadoreño.
  - Interview with Cnel. Juan Alberto Linares Hurtado on 4 Sep 2005, 04 September 2005
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002508
    Cnel. Juan Alberto Linares Hurtado
    Fecha de la entrevista: 4 de septiembre de 2005
    Director del Centro Superior de Estudios Militares del Ejército de Nicaragua.
  - Interview with Cnel. Juan Rodolfo Pardo Aguilar on 6 Dec 2002, 06 December 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002513
    Cnel. Juan Rodolfo Pardo Aguilar
    Fecha de la entrevista: 6 de diciembre de 2002
    Lugar: Puerto Quetzal, Guatemala
    Jefe del Departamento V (Operaciones Psicológicas) de la Base Naval del Pacífico de la Fuerza Naval guatemalteca.
  - Interview with Cnel. Mario Ernesto Sosa Orellana on 4 and 5 Dec 2002, 04 December 2002-05 December 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002515
    Cnel. Mario Ernesto Sosa Orellana
    Fecha de la entrevista: 4/5 de diciembre de 2002
    Lugar: Ciudad de Guatemala, Guatemala
    Jede del Departamento de Material de Guerra del Ejército de Guatemala.
  - Interview with Cnel. Maximo Elías Semenzin Mattarolo on 19 Jun 2008, 19 June 2008
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002511
    Cnel. Maximo Elías Semenzin Mattarolo
    Fecha de la entrevista: 19 de junio de 2008
    Lugar: Washington DC, EUA
    Asesor del Ejército venezolano (Cazador) en El Salvador en 1982.
  - Interview with Cnel. Néctor René Santizo Flores in Feb 2003, 31 January 2003
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002514
    Cnel. Néctor René Santizo Flores
    Fecha de la entrevista: febrero de 2003
    Lugar: Poptum, Peten, Guatemala
    Comandante de la Brigada de Fuerzas Especiales Kaibil del Ejército de Guatemala.
  - Interview with Cnel. Otto Alejandro Romero Orellana in Feb 2002, 31 January 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002512
    Cnel. Otto Alejandro Romero Orellana
    Fecha de la entrevista: febrero de 2002
    Lugar: San Juan Opico, El Salvador
    Comandante de la Brigada de Artillería del Ejército salvadoreño.
  - Interview with Cnel. René Arnoldo Majano Araujo on 2 Dec 2007, 02 December 2007
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002510
    Cnel. René Arnoldo Majano Araujo
    Fecha de la entrevista: 2 de diciembre de 2007
    Ex-Comandante del Escuadrón de Paracaidistas de la Fuerza Aérea salvadoreña.
  - Interview with Eduardo Linares in Feb 2003, 31 January 2003
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002516
    Eduardo Linares
    Fecha de la entrevista: febrero 2003
    Seudónimo Douglas Santamaría, Comandante de las Fuerzas Populares de
    Liberación del Frente Farabundo Martí para la Liberación Nacional (FMLN) de El Salvador.
  - Interview with Gral. Div. Reynaldo Golcher in Jul 2002, 30 June 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002518
    Gral. Div. Reynaldo Golcher
    Fecha de la entrevista: julio de 2002
    Ex-Director de la Policía de Hacienda de El Salvador.
  - Interview with Gral. Div. Adolfo Onecífero Blandon Mejía in Nov 2003, 31 October 2003
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002517
    Gral. Div. Adolfo Onecífero Blandon Mejía
    Fecha de la entrevista: noviembre de 2003
    Ex-Jefe del Estado Mayor General de las Fuerzas Armadas salvadoreñas.
  - Interview with Licda. Victoria Eugrnia Villaruel on 12 Jun 2008, 12 June 2008
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002530
    Licda. Victoria Eugrnia Villaruel
    Fecha de la entrevista: 12 de junio de 2008
    Directora del CELTYV, Centro de Estudios Legales sobre el Terrorismo y sus Victimas.
  - Interview with Myr. Jairo Aguirre on 31 Jul 2004, 31 July 2004
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002519
    Myr. Jairo Aguirre
    Fecha de la entrevista: 31 de julio de 2004
    Comandante de la Unidad de Paracaidistas del Ejército de Nicaragua
  - Interview with Myr. Jorge Gaytan in Aug 2000, 31 July 2000
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002520
    Myr. Jorge Gaytan
    Jefe del Estado Mayor del Comando de Operaciones Especiales del Ejército de Nicaragua.
  - Interview with Myr. José Enrique Munguía Berríos in Sep 2004, 31 August 2004
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002522
    Myr. José Enrique Munguía Berríos
    Fecha de la entrevista: septiembre 2004
    Veterano del Primer Batallón Blindado de la Guardia Nacional de Nicaragua.
  - Interview with Myr. José Romeo Moreno Martínez on 9 Jan 2009, 09 January 2009
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002521
    Myr. José Romeo Moreno Martínez
    Fecha de la entrevista: 9 de enero de 2009
    Veterano de la 4ta. Brigada de Infantería del Ejército salvadoreño.
  - Interview with Remberto Centeno in Oct 2002, 30 September 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002524
    Remberto Centeno
    Seudónimo: desconocido
    Fecha de la entrevista: octubre 2002
    Veterano del Ejército Revolucionario del Pueblo del FMLN salvadoreño
  - Interview with Sgto. Daniel Cortez Rivera in Feb 2002, 31 January 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002525
    Sgto. Daniel Cortez Rivera
    Lugar: Sitio El Niño, El Salvador
    Veterano del Regimiento de Caballería del Ejército salvadoreño
  - Interview with Sgto. Jesús Terezón Valencia on 8 Jan 2009, 08 January 2009
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002527
    Sgto. Jesús Terezón Valencia
    Fecha de la entrevista: 8 de enero de 2009
    Lugar: Ilopango, El Salvador
    Veterano del Escuadrón Aerotransportado de la Fuerza Aérea salvadoreña.
  - Interview with Ssgto. Adm. 1ra. Clase José Ernesto González Sánchez in Mar 2002, 28 February 2002
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002526
    Ssgto. Adm. 1ra. Clase José Ernesto González Sánchez
    Fecha de la entrevista: marzo de 2002
  - Interview with Tte. Jorge Alberto Granados Ventura in Dec 2006, 30 November 2006
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002529
    Tte. Jorge Alberto Granados Ventura
    Fecha de la entrevista: diciembre de 2006
    Lugar: Mejicanos, El Salvador
    Veterano del Batallón de Infantería de Reacción Inmediata Gral. Ramón Belloso.
  - Myr. Herbert Obdulio Segovia Mancilla on 9 Dec 2008, 09 December 2008
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002523
    Myr. Herbert Obdulio Segovia Mancilla
    Fecha de la entrevista: 9 de diciembre de 2008
    Veterano de la Policía de Hacienda de El Salvador
  - Ssgto. Santos Arcadio Castillo Girón on 24 Dec 2005, 24 December 2005
    Use copy reference number: 2009c49_a_0002528
    Ssgto. Santos Arcadio Castillo Girón
    Fecha de la entrevista: 24 de diciembre de 2005
    Veterano del Batallón de Infantería de Reacción Inmediata Atlacatl.
- Sound recording transcripts, 2000-2009 (Box-folder 1)